

■ powersj@fastmail.com | 🈭 powersj.io | 🛅 powersj | 🔾 powersj | 🔞 powersj

Summary _

Software developer with over a decade of experience focused on Linux, open source, clouds, and containers. Advocates for and delivers results with relationships of key partners. Primary development experience centered around Python as well as Golang and Shell scripts.

Experience _____

Canonical Ltd. Remote

SENIOR ENGINEER May 2020 - Current

- Lead the production of Ubuntu cloud images across worldwide major cloud vendors. Specifically, responsible for all engineering interaction and deliverables with Google Cloud including Google Compute Engine (GCE), Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE), and Anthos.
- Engineer new automation for delivery of new cloud features and releases, including educating and advising partners on best practices.
- Ensure timely delivery of critical security CVE updates and fixes for images, while monitoring and enhancing the health of the build process and outputs.

ENGINEERING MANAGER Sep 2018 - May 2020

- · Led and grew the worldwide remote team delivering Ubuntu Server, the number one cloud operating system.
- Proposed and maintained release roadmap of new features and objectives, generated and reviewed specifications of features, and conducted code reviews to ensure completed goals.
- Streamlined the user experience of services on Ubuntu systems by leading the creation of a new supported service tool and premium Ubuntu cloud images.
- Established data-driven decisions through the development of metric collection methodologies to track specific key performance indicators in order to guide future investments by company leadership.

QA ENGINEER Jul 2016 - Sep 2018

- Implemented automated CI and merge review system, setup daily software builds, and wrote integration test framework and test cases for software using containers and cloud deployments.
- Started daily team bug triage process, tooling to review incoming reports for validity and reproducibility, and responses to ensure feedback.

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Fort Collins, Colorado

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb 2014 - Jun 2016

• Enhanced product security and reduced duplicate efforts across the company through the rapid development of HP's own Debianderivative operating system.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jun 2007 - Feb 2014

- Initiated performance characterization testing methodology and qualified the latest I/O technologies to ensure performance across HP's next-generation mission-critical and enterprise servers.
- Conceived automated smoke, integration, and scale tests to run against new product API to reduce development delays and meet quality goals.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Remote

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (3.90/4.00 GPA)

Jan 2014 - May 2016

Colorado State University

Fort Collins, Colorado

BACHELOR OF ARTS AND SCIENCES IN ECONOMICS AND APPLIED COMPUTING TECHNOLOGY (3.55/4.00 GPA)

2005 - 2009

Projects_

- whatsthis—Golang CLI and library to determine if a system is running in a cloud or a container, and hardware the system reports. Used this project to teach myself Golang and ecosystem.
- imgchroot— Quickly customize cloud images in a chroot without the need to boot the image or setup a user on the image with credentials. Also built using Golang.
- powersj.io— Personal blog and website where I write about technologies and share my own learnings.